# **Daniel Burgess**

Full Stack Developer

Phone: 0434 869 784

Email: dan-burgess@hotmail.com

Location: Adelaide SA DOB: 10/10/1993 Portfolio and Links: github.com/DBurgess93 danielburgessportfolio.herokuapp.com linkedin.com/in/daniel-burgess-668176186/

# **Professional Summary**

Ambitious, reliable and functionality first Full-Stack Developer. Looking to engage in a new team environment and apply programming skills, as well as build upon knowledge base in the interest of ongoing improvement.

Graduate of Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp, skilled in both front-end and back-end programming languages/frameworks, as well as databases to build fully functional web applications with a focus on user experience and optimal performance. Portfolio includes both team and individual projects taken from initial design to deployment, using tools to track progress and organise team workflow.

Prior work includes, I year in Freelance Web Development, 8 years in sales and customer relations roles, 6 years in heavily team-based roles, experience in teaching workplace processes, leading small teams and working autonomously.

Previous employees would endorse for having a great attitude, being a hard worker, a people person and someone who is curious and eager to learn.

# **Summary of Skills**

#### **Technical Skills**

- JavaScript
- React.JS
- · Ruby on Rails
- PostgreSQL
- Firebase
- HTML5
- CSS/SCSS, Bootstrap
- React & Svelte (beginner level through Udemy courses)
- Figma
- HubSpot CMS and HubSpot CRM
- REST API and web scraping with Puppeteer
- · Web hosting with Heroku and Bluehost
- GitHub
- WordPress CMS
- Shopify

#### Soft Skills

- Great communication/People Person
- Organisation
- Collaborative Mindset
- Leadership Qualities
- Adaptability
- Problem solving
- Curiosity
- Highly Personable

# **Education**

#### **WEB DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE 2022**

Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp - Bali

## **DIPLOMA OF REMEDIAL MASSAGE 2015**

Endeavour College of Natural Health

**HIGH SCHOOL GRADUATE - 2011** 

Nuriootpa High School

# **Top Projects**

## **Deepwork**

- A Web-app designed to help students track how they spend their study time, analyse their data for a better understanding of their studying habits and motivate them to reach a state of deep focus.
- Tech-stack: Ruby on Rails, SASS, HTML, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Figma.

### De-fit

- A Web-app built to help bring together those who are in need of a fitness space and those who have one to share.
- Tech-stack: Ruby on Rails, SASS, HTML, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Figma.

## SiteForge.io

- Start-up Junior Role: An Al wireframe and content generator that builds the basic structure of web pages tailored to your brand.
- Tech-stack: Rust, JavaScript, TypeScript, Svelte.

### **Freelance Web Development**

 Design and build various websites for small start-ups as part of The RED Group initiative. The RED Group help people with disabilities start their own Micro Enterprise. I work closely with The Red Group and the enterprise founders to develop an online presence solution through building and maintaining their website. Predominantly working with WordPress, Squarespace, and Shopify CMS.

# **Work Experience**

# Web Developer | The Kingdom | Sep 2023 - Jan 2024

- A Marketing Technology company. Predominantly working within the HubSpot CMS with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, HubL, and JavaScript.
- HubSpot CMS and Custom Development, creating and maintaining modules, templates and themes with clients branding.
- Wordpress CMS and Custom Development.
- Testing, debugging, and correcting design flaws in legacy code.
- SEO and accessibility optimization.
- Workflow and email automation.
- Consistent training and professional development, focussed on Hubspot CRM, Hubspot CMS and design practices.

## Internal Sales | Amorini Australia | Aug 2021 - Sep 2022

- Managing all custom-made kitchen parts for every order.
- First point of call for customers, communicating to ensure custom products meet specification requirements.
- Improving online portal structures for kitchen sales software.
- Logistics Coordinating stock compiling for orders to be sent to site and between factories, tracking stock holdings and re-orders.
- Data entry using Servicem8 and EQ Business Management Software.

## Sales Rep | Camfil Australia (Airepure) | Jun 2018 - Dec 2019

- Building and maintaining customer relations through Sales calls.
- Provide expert technical advice through collaboration with internal engineering teams.
- Improving manufacturing processes, managing customer expectations.
- Analyzing tenders to quote projects from mechanical contractors.
- Sales research to secure early sales/tenders.
- Logistics co-ordination, Stock control, re-ordering, and data entry using Sage Accpac and Realtime Logistics.

#### Other Notable Roles

Freelance Web Dev | Own Business | Feb 2023 - Present Support Worker | Own Business | March 2023 - Present Mapping operator | Voxel Maps | Jan 2023 - Mar 2023 Cellar hand | Treasure Wine Estates | Jan 2020 - Aug 2021 Delivery Driver | OzHarvest | April 2020 - Oct 2020 Remedial Therapist | Own Business | Mar 2014 - July 2018 Duty Manager | Barossa Rex Centre | Jan 2012 - Aug 2015